A Register of the Russkii Obshche-voinskii soiuz (ROVS) Records
Hoover Institution Archives
Russkii Obshche-voinskii soiuz (ROVS) Records
1919-1986
2008C86
Russkii Obshche-voinskii soiuz
18 microfilm reels 2.7 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
These records consist of select documents of the Russkii obshche-voinskii soiuz, (ROVS), the Russian All-Military Union. Formed by General Petr N. Vrangel' in 1924, ROVS managed to preserve the military structure of the demilitarized White Army in exile, while integrating its members into civilian life. ROVS played an important role in redefining the White Army's ideology, and provided essential support to its members in emigration. These records include detailed lists of ROVS members, correspondence, circulars, orders, and reports.
Administrative Information
Access
The collection is open for research
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2008
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternative Forms of Material Available
The entire collection is available on Microfilm
Location of Original Materials
Holy Trinity Orthodox Seminary, Jordanville, New York
Scope and Content of Collection
These records consist of select documents of the Russkii obshche-voinskii soiuz, ROVS, the Russian All-military union. Formed by General Petr N. Vrangel' in 1924, ROVS managed to preserve the military structure of the demilitarized White Army in exile, while integrating its members into civilian life. ROVS played an important role in redefining the White Army's ideology, and provided essential support to its members in emigration.
These records include detailed lists of ROVS members, correspondence, circulars, orders, and reports.
Included are documents that predate the formation of the Russkii obshche-voinskii soiuz, such as circulars and orders of the White Army under General A. I. Denikin, and orders of the Russian Army under General P. N. Vrangel's command.
Of particular importance is a collection of eight boxes of index cards, dating to 1924-1925, which provides personal information of members of the Gallipoli veteran's association, included the numbers of distributed commemorative Gallipoli crosses.
Detailed processing and preservation microfilming for these materials were made possible by a generous grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities and by matching funds from the Hoover Institution and the Holy Trinity Seminary. The grant also provides depositing a microfilm copy in the Hoover Institution Archives. The original materials remain in the Holy Trinity Seminary Archives as its property. A transfer table indicating corresponding box and reel numbers is appended to this register. Any views, findings, conclusions or recommendations expressed in these materials do not necessarily represent those of the National Endowment for the Humanities.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into one series: Office file
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the online catalog.
Subjects
Obshchestvo revnitelei russkoi voennoi stariny.; Russia (Territory under White Armies). Dobrovol'cheskaia armiia.; Russkaia Armiia.; Russkii obshche-voinskii soiuz.; Vrangel', Petr Nikolaevich.; World War, 1914-1918.
Related Material
V. K. Abdank-Kossovskii Papers, Holy Trinity Orthodox Seminary
Sviatoslav Varlaamovich Denisov Papers, Holy Trinity Orthodox Seminary
Petr Nikolaevich Krasnov Papers, Holy Trinity Orthodox Seminary
ROVS Records, Bakhmeteff Archives, Columbia University
Collection Contents
- Office file, 1919-1986 and undated. (Box 1)
  Bulletins, certificate, circulars, clippings, correspondence, financial accounts, guidelines, inventories, lists, menus, minutes, notes, orders, pamphlets, questionnaire, receipts, speeches, and statutes. Arranged alphabetically by physical form
  - General, 1948 and undated (Folder 1: 1)
  - Circulars, 1925-1965 and undated (Folder 1: 2)
  - Clippings, 1929-1931 and undated (Folder 1: 3)
  - Correspondence, 1921-1969 and undated
    - General, 1931-1969 (Folder 1: 4)
    - Arkhangel'skii, Aleksei Petrovich, 1939-1954 (Folder 1: 5)
    - Kovalevskii, Vladimir Grigor'evich, 1954-1955 (Folder 1: 6)
    - Krasnov, Petr Nikolaevich, 1921-1927 and undated (Folder 1: 7)
    - Lampe, Aleksei Aleksandrovich von, 1951-1955 (Folder 1: 8)
    - Miller, Evgenii Karlovich, 1923-1928 (Folder 1: 9)
    - Protasovich, Viktor Aleksandrovich, 1955-1958 (Folder 1: 10)
    - Shatilov, Pavel Nikolaevich, 1933 (Folder 1: 11)
    - Shchavinskii, Vadim Vsevolodovich, 1954 and undated (Folder 1: 12)
    - Vrangel', Petr Nikolaevich, 1921-1936 and undated (Folder 1: 13)
  - Financial accounts, 1924; 1932 (Folder 1: 14)
  - Guidelines, 1932 (Folder 1: 15)
  - Lists, 1920-1986 and undated
    - General, 1932-1934 and undated (Folder 1: 16)
    - 1-yi armeiskii korpus, 1925 and undated (Folder 1: 17-18)
    - Byvshie slushateli vysshikh voennykh kursov, 1957 (Folder 1: 19)
    - Delo o chislennom sostave obshchevoinskogo soiuza, 1924-1926 and undated (Folder 1: 20)
    - Deceased members, undated (Folder 1: 21)
    - Gallipoli veterans union, 1924-1925. (Box 2)
      Index cards with personal information of members
      - A-C
      - C-G (Box 3)
      - G-K (Box 4)
      - K-L (Box 5)
      - M-P (Box 6)
      - P-S (Box 7)
      - S-T (Box 8)
      - T-Z (Box 9)
    - Kornilovskii polk, undated (Box-folder 10: 1-2)
    - Ofitserskie i klassnye chiny Russkoi armii, 1920-1925 (Folder 10: 3)
    - Pervopokhodniki, 1986 (Folder 10: 4)
    - Soiuz tverskikh iunkerov, 1958 (Folder 10: 5)
  - Orders, 1924-1966 and undated
    - General
      - 1924 (Folder 10: 6)
      - 1925 (Folder 10: 7)
      - 1926 (Folder 10: 8)
      - 1927 (Folder 10: 9)
      - 1928 (Folder 10: 10)
      - 1929 (Folder 10: 11)
      - 1930 (Box-folder 11: 1)
      - 1931 (Folder 11: 2)
      - 1932 (Folder 11: 3)
      - 1933 (Folder 11: 4)
      - 1934 (Folder 11: 5)
      - 1935 (Folder 11: 6)
      - 1936 (Folder 11: 7)
      - 1937 (Folder 11: 8)
      - 1938 (Folder 11: 9)
      - 1939 (Folder 11: 10)
      - 1940 (Folder 11: 11)
      - 1941 (Folder 11: 12)
      - 1942 (Folder 11: 13)
      - 1943 (Folder 11: 14)
      - 1948-1955 (Folder 11: 15)
      - 1956-1960 (Folder 11: 16)
      - 1961-1966 (Folder 11: 17)
    - Nikolai Nikolaevich, Grand Duke, undated (Folder 11: 18)
  - Inventory
    - 1921-1923 (Folder 11: 19)
    - Dragomirov, A. M., 1956 (Folder 11: 20)
  - Menus and programs, 1933-1954 (Folder 11: 21)
  - Minutes, 1942 (Box-folder 12: 1)
  - Pamphlets, 1932 and undated (Folder 12: 2)
  - Printed matter, 1947 (Folder 12: 3)
  - Questionnaire, undated (Folder 12: 4)
  - Statutes, 1924-1929 (Folder 12: 5)
  - Subject file, 1919-1972 and undated
    - Bogaevskii, Afrikan Petrovich, 1923. (Folder 12: 6)
      Typescript, memoir
    - Denikin, Anton Ivanovich, 1924-1972 and undated. (Folder 12: 7)
      Includes biography, clippings, and correspondence
    - Gosudarstvennoe soveshchanie, undated typed copy of minutes of 1917 (Folder 12: 8)
    - Gvardeiskoe ob"edinenie, 1952. (Folder 12: 9)
      Reference publication
    - Ivanov, Sergei Mikhailovich, 1960. (Folder 12: 10)
      Certificate
    - Miller, Evgenii Karlovich, 1931-1934. (Folder 12: 11)
      Typescript of speeches
    - Obshchestvo revnitelei russkoi voennoi stariny, 1946-1968 and undated. (Folder 12: 12)
      Includes clippings, correspondence, notes, and receipts
    - Laws, compendium, 1919. (Folder 12: 13)
      Printed copy
    - Russia (Territory under White Armies). Dobrovol'cheskaia armiia. Orders
      - 1919-1920
        - Numbers 561, 579, 845 (Folder 12: 14)
        - Numbers 1-59, 216, 282 (Folder 12: 15)
        - Numbers 1-250 (Folder 12: 16)
        - Numbers 2-105 (Box-folder 13: 1)
        - Numbers 96-184 (Folder 13: 2)
        - Numbers 501-1000 (Folder 13: 3)
        - Numbers 1001-1251 (Folder 13: 4)
        - Numbers 1252-1500 (Box-folder 14: 1)
        - Numbers 1822-2199 (Folder 14: 2)
        - Numbers 2200-3356 (incomplete) (Folder 14: 3)
      - 1919-1922 (Folder 14: 4)
    - Russkaia armiia. Orders (Box-folder 15: 1)
      - General
        - 1920
        - 1921 (Folder 15: 2-6)
        - 1922 (Box-folder 16: 1-4)
        - 1923 (Folder 16: 5)
      - Voennye chiny (Box 17)
        - 1920 (Folder 17: 1)
        - 1921 (Folder 17: 2-3)
        - 1922 (Folder 17: 4-6)
        - 1923 (Box-folder 18: 1)
        - 1924 (Folder 18: 2)
    - Russkii korpus, 1951. (Folder 18: 3)
      Speech, printed copy
    - Skoblin, Nikolai V., 1931-1938 and undated. (Folder 18: 4)
      Includes bulletins, correspondence, orders
    - Soiuz chinov Russkogo korpusa, 1962. (Folder 18: 5)
      Excerpt from minutes, and circular
    - Vitkovskii, Vladimir Konstantinovich, 1923. (Folder 18: 6)
      Reports
    - Vnutrenniaia liniia, 1935-1938 and undated. (Folder 18: 7)
      Includes circulars, clippings, orders, and pamphlet
    - Vrangel', Petr Nikolaevich, undated. (Folder 18: 8)
      Biography, printed copy
    - Zarubezhnyi soiuz russkikh voennykh invalidov, 1957-1966 and undated. (Folder 18: 9)
      Includes circulars, correspondence, minutes, and statutes